本
本字
本字幕
本字幕由
本字幕由 文
本字幕由 文正
本字幕由 文正（
本字幕由 文正（2
本字幕由 文正（28
本字幕由 文正（284
本字幕由 文正（2844
本字幕由 文正（28444
本字幕由 文正（284444
本字幕由 文正（2844446
本字幕由 文正（28444468
本字幕由 文正（284444682
本字幕由 文正（284444682）
本字幕由 文正（284444682）制
本字幕由 文正（284444682）制作
943-66-2291. Pension Services, please.
943-66-2291. 请接养老中心 谢谢
Thank you, Mr. Moses, please hold for your representative.
感谢致电 摩西先生 请稍候您的专员
Hi, this is Sarah.
嗨 我是莎拉
It's Frank Moses.
我是弗兰克•摩西
Frank. What's going on?
弗兰克 最近怎么样
Not much.
老样子
I just called because they didn't send that check out again.
我只是咨询一下 我没有收到养老金支票
I can't believe they haven't worked this out by now.
简直不敢相信 到现在都没有核算完
I'll make sure they send another one out today.
我向您保证 他们今天会再寄送一张
I'm so sorry.
非常抱歉
Well, what are you gonna do?
好吧 你准备怎么办
So how's your avocado?
你种的鳄梨怎样了
It's got two green leaves on it.
长出两篇绿叶了
I told you, you could grow something.
早告诉你可以种点东西
Well, it was pretty close. It was life or death.
是吗 我也说不清 它究竟会死会活
I'm not kidding. It could have gone either way.
真的 它随时可能爆出意外
How's your day going?
你过得怎么样
My day? My day sucks.
我吗 糟糕透了
Your day sucks?
糟糕透了
Right now I just want to travel.
现在 我只想去旅行
I'm thinking Chile. Sounds like an adventure. I don't know.
我在考虑智利 像冒险似的 我也不请楚
You ever been to Chile?
你去过智利吗
You have? What's it like?
是吗 那儿怎样
Mountains.
到处是山
That's it?
就这样
Well, it was night, I...
当时是晚上 我…
Look, I gotta go.
啊 我得挂了
Okay. Sure.
好吧
No, sorry, it's just Gladys.
不好意思 是格雷迪
What?
有事
"It was night."
当时是晚上
Hi, Mr. Moses!
早啊 摩西先生
Did you start that new book? -I did.
你开始读那本书了吗  -开始了
And, what's it called?
叫什么来着
It's called Love's Savage Secret.
《爱的残酷秘密》
Nice.
很不错
Is it any good?
有什么亮点
It's terrible. I love it. It's awful.
很惊险 但我很喜欢 很刺激
It's about this fashion designer
一位时装设计师
and his supermodel girlfriend, and they get recruited
和他的超模女友 被CIA招募
by the CIA to stop an assassination at the Milan spring shows.
在米兰春季时装秀 阻止一场暗杀
Well, who doesn't like Milan in the spring?
有人不喜欢米兰春装秀
I guess.
可能吧
Anyway, I gotta do something for excitement.
不管怎样 我得干点激动人心的事情
My landlady keeps trying to set me up with her bridge partners' kids.
我房东太太 一直撮合我和她牌友的孩子
She just told me she thinks I'm gay.
她对我说 她曾怀疑我是同性恋
I try not to judge.
我不做评论
What? Shut up! I'm not gay.
去死 我不是同性恋
So here's something weird.
真是有点难以启齿
I'm actually gonna be in Kansas City next week.
下周 我要去堪萨斯城
In person?
私人性质
That could be a bad idea.
这可不好
It could be.
可以的
You still there?
还在吗
Why don't you call me when you get to town?
那你过来后 给我打个电话吧
Okay. Bye.
好的 拜拜
Okay, bye.
拜拜
All right.
好吧
Come in, Unit One.
收到吗 一队
Unit One, respond.
一队 请回答
Aren't you going to invite me in?
你不打算邀请我进家吗
No, I don't think so.
没这个必要
But I bought you dinner!
我请你吃晚饭
And you live with your mother.
你竟然和妈妈一起住
Awesome.
糟透了
Yeah, of course. You have no job.
当然 还没有工作
You, mister, are not getting any of this.
你根本就不理解这个
It's me. Frank.
是我 弗兰克
The avocado?
鳄梨
Why are you here? Get out of my house!
你怎么在这儿 出去
I told you to call first.
我告诉你要先打电话
I'm not gonna hurt you.
我不会伤害你的
Would you just listen to me? Please? Stop that!
你能好好听我说吗 快住手
Get back. Go away. Stay away from me!
退后 出去 别碰我
Is that my bag?
那是我的包吗
Yeah.
是呀
You packed it?
你已经打包好了
Yes.
是的
Did you vacuum?
你是隐形人吗
A little, yeah, it was messy.
是 有一点乱
Get back. Get out!
退后 出去
Please. We have to leave. Right now. Stop it.
听我说 我们必须离开这 快住手
Just listen to me, please!
听我说好吗
Someone is trying to kill me.
有人要杀我
What are you doing? Listen to me!
你在干什么 听我说
They've been trying to kill you, too.
他们也要杀了你
Why would anyone want to kill me?
为什么有人想杀了我
Because we've been under surveillance.
因为我们被监视了
They've been listening to our conversations.
他们监听到了我们通话
Why?
为什么
Because of the way I talk to you.
因为我跟你说话很温柔
What?
什么
They know I like you.
他们知道我喜欢你
Listen to me. Right now. Out the back door.
听我说 就现在 我们从后门出去
No way! No!
没门儿 不
Don't get me wrong, I know it's crazy.
别把我想歪了 我知道这很疯狂
Don't think that …I don't think this is crazy.
别以为…其实我觉得这很正常
And it…couldn't be more different than how I'd hoped to meet you for the first time.
这跟我设想的 与你第一次会面的场景 也很不一样
But sometimes things happen.
但有些时候 事情就这么发生了
And I just hope that someday you and I could be
我只希望 有一天 你和我
sitting somewhere, comfortably
躺在什么地方 舒适的
and look back on this as the great, big adventure that it is.
回顾我们所一起经历过的 伟大的冒险
I'm a little hungry, too. What should we get?
我也饿了 你想吃什么
Pizza.
披萨
Listen.
听着
Yeah, lots of boys get bullied at school.
学校里 很多孩子会中弹
I know, but you can't solve it by intervening like that.
我知道 但你那样干预解决不了问题
No, I don't agree with you.
不 我不赞同
I know, it's hard.
我知道 很难
I'll talk to him about it when I get home.
我回家后 会跟他说的
No, I should be on time tonight.
不 晚上我会准时回家的
Milk, two percent? Okay, love you, bye.
牛奶？ 百分之二。好的 爱你 再见
Listen. I can make you rich.
听着 我可以给你钱
Don't you know who I am?
你不知道我是谁吗
Of course, I do.
我当然知道
This is off the books. Total blackout.
这段儿不要记录 完全不存在
Yes, ma'am.
是的 长官
There's your target.
这是你的目标
Retired analyst.
退休分析员
He was CIA.
他是CIA
Is that a problem?
有问题吗
No.
没有
If you let me go now, I won't press charges.
如果你现在放我走 我不会起诉你的
-There's no hard feelings. -We're way past charges.
-没什么大事 -这事早超过起诉了
How do I always attract losers like you?
我怎么总是跟你这种混球交往呢
I was in the CIA.
我以前是CIA
Yeah, I bet you were. I'll bet you're a spy.
是啊 你是CIA 还是间谍呢
I have to go see someone now...
我得出门去见个人
You're just gonna make me sit here? Like this?
你就把我这么捆在这儿吗
You couldn't be safer. No one knows where you are.
这最安全了 没人知道你在这儿
Oh, no. Don't do it.
不 别封嘴
-Just hold still. -Don't please. I don't want it.
-好好待这儿 -别这样 我不想粘这个
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
抱歉 抱歉 抱歉
Your eyes are so beautiful.
你眼睛真漂亮
Want to watch TV?
想看电视吗
Be back soon.
我很快回来
Is that thing acting up again?
又有雪花了
Oh, hi, Marna, yeah.
哦 玛娜
Give it a rap, will ya? See if you could get it going for me.
转转天线 好吗 看看能不能弄好
Of course.
当然
I don't know why you don't fix this old thing.
我不知道 你为什么不好好修修这老古董
Better picture.
好极了
-Try a little bit more to the left.
往左一点
That's just perfect.
漂亮极了
Thank you very much, Marna.
非常谢谢你 玛娜
Unbelievable.
不可思议
Should be ashamed of yourself.
真老不要脸
It's nice to see you, kid.
见到你真好兴 孩子
It's good to see you, too.
见到你也很高兴
So what's up?
最近怎么样
Met a girl.
见个女孩儿
No.
不会吧
Complicated.
真的
Got a visit from a wet team. At my house, 24 hours ago.
道上有一群人  闯进我家 24 小时前
Did you ID any of them?
有什么线索吗
Kinda.
算有吧
This used to be a gentleman's game.
你以前做事很温柔的
And you know I love you. Bye.
你知道我爱你 拜拜
Independent South African hit team
南非独立杀手组织
suspected of killing a New York Times reporter.
涉嫌杀害一名纽约时报的记者
Stephanie Chan. You know her?
斯丹芬妮•陈 你认识吗
No.
不认识
Somebody has a serious hard-on for you, kid.
看来有人盯上你了
Yeah.
是啊
But why now? I'm retired.
但为什么呢 我已经退休了
Just have to dig some more.
在找找看有什么新发现
Watch your back, too.
你也多加警惕
I'm 80 years old, I got stage 4 liver cancer.
我已经80了 肝癌末期
-What the hell can they do to me? -They can still shoot you.
-他们能对我怎样 -他们仍然能崩了你
I never thought this would happen to me.
我从没想过这事会发生在我身上
What?
什么
Getting old.
人老珠黄
I mean, Vietnam, Afghanistan.
想当年… 越南 阿富汗
Green Springs Rest Home?
现在 养老院 等死
Go figure.
去干吧
So Moses made 22 calls to Pension Services and that didn't stand out to you?
摩西给养老中心打了22通电话 你都没发现
Unbelievable.
笨蛋
Have Endercott intercept the girl at the Hotel Capri.
监听到 那个女孩儿停在卡普里宾馆
Hey, Mike, change of plans.
麦克 计划有变
She's just fine.
她没事儿
I can take you home.
我能送你回家
I gotta take you down to the station first to get your statement.
我先送你回警局做笔录
Then there's a couple of federal guys that are gonna want to talk to you.
然后 几位联邦干员 要跟你了解点情况
I gotta say, I think you're pretty amazing for breaking free and keeping it together like you did.
不得不说 你能从那里解脱 并表现的如此平静 真令人惊讶
That's impressive.
印象深刻
I'm gonna go back and get my purse...
我得回去拿我的钱包
I can have somebody bring it downtown for you.
我叫人帮你带过来
Get in the car!
进车
Let me go! You're hurting me.
放开我 你弄疼我了
Am I gonna die?
我要死了吗
No. You just need some sleep.
你只是会多睡会儿
I may vomit.
我想吐
This is just like Love's Savage Secret.
这就像 《爱的残酷秘密》
I am high.
我有点晕
You have such beautiful green eyes.
你那绿色的双眸帅呆了
You really are CIA.
你还真是 CIA
Officer down. Corner of North Peters and Conti.
警员受伤 北皮特-康蒂街角
Suspect is a white male, 30s, black suit and a tie,
嫌疑人为白种男性 30多 黑色制服领带
driving a black Tahoe.
驾驶 黑色塔虎
Freeze! Put your weapon on the ground!
不许动 放下枪
Put your weapon on the ground now!
把枪放在地上
Right now!
快
So you're saying this was CIA sanctioned?
这么说 这是中情局内部制裁
All right, Thelma, thanks. I owe you one. Bye.
好的 希尔玛 谢谢 欠你个人情
So it's like that, huh?
结束了吗
Yeah. It's like that.
没错 你完了
Where are we?
我们在哪儿
How did we get to New York City?
我们怎么会在纽约
Wow, I really hate you right now.
现在我恨透你了
I was just hoping you'd be a little more understanding of the situation.
我只是希望你能 多明白一点 现在的状况
I was hoping not to get kidnapped. Or drugged.
我只是希望别被绑架 或下药
I was hoping you'd have hair.
我希望你有头发
So it looks like none of our dreams are coming true, at the moment.
貌似迄今为止 我设想的美梦 一个都没实现
Sorry about that.
不好意思
Thanks for saving me. I guess.
谢谢你救了我
No problem.
没关系
Not my best first date.
不算最好的约会
Not my worst, either.
也不是最差的
Until we find out who's trying to kill us, you're gonna have to stay with me.
在找到他们为什么杀我们之前 你得跟我待在一起
For how long?
多长时间
I don't know.
我也不知道
Whoever's trying to kill us also killed a New York Times reporter.
想杀我的人 也杀了一个纽约时报的记者
She used to live in Chinatown.
生前住在唐人街
Okay. Here we go. Let's come in here. Right here. Wait a second.
这边走 进去 就这儿 等一下
You just hang onto this tape.
帮我拿着胶带
No, you said we were just gonna talk to her.
你不是说我们只跟她谈谈话吗
We are. This'll help.
是啊 这个有用
The woman just lost her daughter.
人家女儿 刚刚被害了
You can't just go around duct taping everyone.
你不能总是走进去用胶带绑人
People are basically kind of decent.
大家都是正经人
That hasn't always been my experience.
我的生活里 这个不常见
Let me try and talk to her.
让我试着和她谈
-What? -Just let me do it.
-什么 -就让我去说
They told me to be patient.
他们告诉我耐心点
The police have done nothing.
警方什么也不干
They said it was just a burglary, but nothing was missing.
他们说是入室盗窃 但东西一样都没丢
She was scared.
她被害了
We're hoping we can do more.
我们希望能多做点
You worked with my Stephanie?
你是斯丹芬妮同事吗
She sent me this.
她给我寄了这个
I got it in the mail on the day she died.
她死那天我收到的
What does this mean?
这是什么意思
I don't know.
我不知道
I tried dialing the numbers.
我拨了上面的号码
Police had no idea.
警察也没头绪
Where did Stephanie go to college?
斯丹芬妮在哪儿上的大学
Why are we here again?
我们现在去哪儿
Those numbers on Stephanie Chan's postcard
斯丹芬妮•陈 明信片上的数字
are actually a call number for a book.
是书的条形码
Call numbers start with letters.
以字母开头的数字
In the Library of Congress, yeah.
国会图书馆
In Harvard-Yenching, it's a classification for Asian literature.
在 哈佛-燕京 亚洲文学类
How could you possibly know that?
你怎么知道这些的
几年前 我住在 武汉
You speak Chinese?
你会讲汉语
Unbelievable.
不可思议
Hank Maestriano died 2 weeks ago. Car crash.
汉克•马斯特尼奥 两周前身故 车祸
Daniel McGinty. Heart attack. Last week.
丹尼尔•麦克金帝 心脏病 上周
But if this is a hit list, why is this guy still alive? Gabriel Singer.
但如果这就是打击名单 为什么这家伙还活着 加布里尔•辛格
Flies cargo planes.
运输机驾驶员
That's a good question.
问得好
Hell of a mess.
一团糟啊
Come on.
快接呀
Joe Matheson, please.
请接 乔•马希森
Hold on.
等一下
Marna.
玛娜
Hello?
你是
What?
怎么了
Joe.
乔死了
Frank Moses is not a retired analyst who's never worked in the field.
弗兰克•摩西 可不是什么退休分析员 从没上过一线
This guy has a history.
这家伙深藏不露
That's a file number.
这是档案编号
You need to visit the back room.
你去地下室查一下
You're going to meet the Records Keeper.
拜会一下档案管理员
I didn't even know this place existed.
我甚至都不知道存在这种地方
It doesn't.
的确不存在
Frank Moses' file.
弗兰克•摩西的档案
You gotta be kidding me.
这事开玩笑吧
Frank Moses was one of the most effective black op agents we've ever had.
弗兰克•摩西 是迄今我们最优秀的特工之一
He retired drug-lords, terrorists. Hell, he toppled governments.
他抓过毒贩、恐怖分子 甚至扳倒过政府
He was truly gifted.
他真是天赋异秉
Why was he retired?
他因何退休
He got old.
老了
Then some thumb-sucker came along and tagged him "RED."
后来一些大佬过来 给他标记为“RED”
Red?
红色
Yeah. RED. R-E-D. "Retired: Extremely Dangerous."
是 红色 R-E-D：退休、极端 危险
They don't make them like that anymore.
就这样把档案全毁了
Thanks.
谢谢
I'm gonna need a data haunt.
我要一个数据师
Every flake he was ever involved in. Every agent he's ever run.
他涉及的所有资料 参与的每个项目
I want NSA telephone surveillance, voice recognition...
我要国安局的电话监控 声音识别
We have to find Marvin Boggs.
我们必须找到 马文•博格斯
Marvin died two years ago in a fire.
马文两年前火灾去世了
Marvin has died many times.
马文死了好多次了
Can we have that one?
我们能开那个吗
All we need is a banjo.
原来我们要找个非洲土著
Keep your voice down.
声音小点儿
Don't make any sudden moves.
别随便乱动
Just stay close to me.
紧跟着我
-Don't use your cell phone. -You took my cell phone.
-别用手机 -你已经把手机扔了
Don't talk about cell phones. Don't talk about satellites.
别提手机 别提卫星
Seriously?
有这么严重吗
Why are you trying to kill me?
你为什么要杀我
I'm not trying to kill you!
我没想杀你
Oh, yeah. You are.
别废话 你当然想
Why would I be trying to kill you?
我为什么要杀你
Because the last time we met, I tried to kill you.
因为上次我们见面时 我要杀你
That was a long time ago.
那已经很久了
Some people hold on to things like that.
有些人就是非常坚持
I'm not trying to kill you. Okay?
我不想杀你 好吗
So that makes us friends.
我们和解好吗
Right?
好吗
Right.
好吧
Good.
很好
You wanna take that knife out of my balls now?
把刀从我裤裆拿开好吗
Who is she?
她是谁
Sarah. She's not trying to kill you either.
莎拉 她也不会杀你的
I don't stay in the open.
我从不待在露天处
Come on, I'll show you the house.
走吧 我带你到屋里转转
What's that?
那屋子算什么
Decoy.
诱饵
He lives in a car?
他就住在小轿车里
Come on in.
进来吧
Why do you live here when you have the other place?
既然你有房子 为什么还住在这里
When the helicopter passed over the house last year
去年 直升机从这里飞过
and I could feel their eyes on me.
我就感觉他们盯上我了
Wet like peaches.
黑手无处不在
I have a list here.
我这里有张名单
It was written by a reporter who's now dead.
一个记者写的 然后被杀了
Along with everyone whose names are on that list.
受访的所有人名字都在名单上
Well, almost everyone.
几乎所有人
Frank, how many times have I told you?
弗兰克 我告诉你多少遍了
You cannot trust the system!
绝不能相信体系
I told you when you're in the system, they switch the flip and you're done.
你进CIA时我就说了 他们一翻脸你就玩完
Man, satellites, cell phones,
人哪 卫星 手机
chips, net, the web, the dentist...
芯片 网络 互联 牙医
Marvin!
马文
That list is the one we need help with.
我们需要这份名单帮忙
I gotta check the files.
我去调查一下
Of course you do. Thanks, man.
当然了 谢谢你 伙计
This guy's insane.
这家伙疯了
Well, he thought he was the subject of
a secret government mind control project.
他认为自己 被政府的一个思想控制项目秘密监控了
This'll take a minute.
这得要几分钟
Sure.
当然
As it turns out,
于是乎
he really was being given daily doses of LSD for 11 years.
他还真每天吃 半人工致幻剂 吃了11 年
In that case, he looks great. -Fantastic.
若是十一年 那他精神倒挺好 -奇迹
Got it. Guatemala. Fall 1981.
好了 危地马拉 1981年秋
Five of the guys on this list were there,
not including us.
除我们外 名单上有五个人当时都在那
San Benito. Just outside.
圣贝尼托 就在边上
Injun territory.
印第安领土
Was a little village.Everybody was killed. Civilians.
是个小村庄 所有人都被杀了 都是平民
They told us, "Go in there. Clean it up.
他们让我们 “深入 打扫干净”
"Make it look like it never happened."
“就像什么都没有发生过”
You think everyone on this list was there?
你确认名单上所有人当时都在场吗
Damn it.
见鬼
Damn it!
天哪
Do you know what's wrong with this country?
你知道 这国家出什么毛病了吗
They're all trying to kill us?
他们都想干掉我们吗
Exactly!
对极了
Is there anybody still alive on that list?
名单上还有人幸存吗
Gabriel Singer.
加布里尔·辛格
Frank!
弗兰克
I never thought I'd say this again.
真不敢相信我又得来一遍
I am getting the pig!
我得带上我的猪
Who's she talking to?
她给谁打电话
Just take it easy.
别紧张
Frank, we gotta get rid of this broad.
弗兰克 我们得避免这种大众通讯
I know a great place, just up the road. Lots of alligators.
我知道一个地方 就在路对面 很多鳄鱼
We're not getting rid of the broad.
我们不能不用这些东西
I like her.
我喜欢她
What's the angle?
哪方面
No angle. I like her.
没哪方面 就是喜欢
So, they pull her voice from the pay phone,
看吧 他们会从电话里提取她的声音
probably right now,
很可能就此时此刻
install the recognition software and back-trace it to Singer.
通过语音识别软件 追踪到辛格
So then we show up, they bring out the satellite,
我们一露头 他们就卫星定位
and we're fried with Y-rays.
我们就被激光枪瞄准了
How you doing?
还好吗
Good, fine.
很好 谢谢
November niner 748.
N-9-748
Singer is going to be in Mobile tomorrow.
辛格明天会在 Mobile 当班
We can catch him at the airfreight terminal.
我们可以 在机场塔台 找到他
How about that?
你们看怎么样
No, please! No!
住手 求你了
You smell like Washington.
你闻着像华府间谍
Who do you work for?
你为谁工作
Coldwell Banker, I'm a real estate agent! Please, don't hurt me.
寇威尔·班克 我只是个房产中介 求你 别伤害我
No, no. Who do you work for?
不对 不对 你到底是谁
Who do you work for?
哪个部门的
Marvin!
马文
Frank, she's one of them. She's been following us.
弗兰克 她是他们一伙的 她在跟踪我们
There's a camera in her bag. I'm gonna kill her now.
她包里有摄像机 我得干掉她
No, please don't kill...Don't let him kill me! Please!
不 求你不要杀我…别让他杀我 求你了
Marvin, just wait, would you, please?
马文 等等 好吗 拜托了
Marvin. Look. Marvin.
马文 看看 马文
No camera in the bag.
包里没相机
Go, ma'am, now. Now.
走吧 女士 快走
Get a car.
找辆车
Try not to kill anyone.
别让任何人送命
She was following us, Frank.
她肯定在跟踪我们 弗兰克
Sorry.
抱歉
"She has a camera in her purse, we have to kill her?"
她包里有相机 我们得干掉她
Seriously?
没开玩笑吧
See you in a minute.
呆会儿见
Gabriel?
加布里尔
Right? Gabriel Singer?
对吗 加布里尔·辛格
What's this about?
有什么事吗
Guatemala. 1981. San Benito.
危地马拉 1981年 圣贝尼托
I can't talk to you.
没什么好说的
Pair beats ace.
你们人多
I got one for you.
我有个问题
What did this twice-decorated, west Texas Jew-boy Marine pilot
一个来自西得克萨斯的犹太男人 受过两次表彰的海军飞行员
say to the Chinese New York Times reporter?
会跟纽约时报的华裔记者说什么
I give up.
我不知道
Nothing. I didn't tell her a damn thing.
木有 我没透露给她任何东西
The reporter's dead now.
那记者已经死了
And everyone she spoke to is either dead
or a target.
她采访过的人 也都死了 或成了目标
That includes you.
包括你
Oh, Christ.
上帝啊
They had me fly this guy out there in the dead of night.
那晚他们让我 带这个人飞出来
Hairy little airstrip in the middle of nowhere.
路中间一条糟糕兮兮的跑道
He was CIA, some dorky little spook in a suit and tie.
那人是CIA 傻乎乎的西装领带 寝食不安的样子
Remember that guy?
记得这家伙吗
-Black glasses. -Yeah. He was giving the orders.
-墨镜那个 -就是他下的命令
He picked up a package and I flew him back out.
他收拾了东西 我带他出来
What was the package?
收拾什么东西
It wasn't a what.
不是什么东西
It was a who.
是一个人
Frank! Frank!
弗兰克 弗兰克
It's that helicopter.
那架直升机
We're in an airport. So...
我们在机场 当然…
It's the same helicopter.
是同一架直升机
November niner 748 Charlie.
N-9-748-C
See? Frank, November niner 74...
对吧 弗兰克 N-9-74…
Is that a 4?
那是 4  吗
This is a 4. Charlie.
这就是4 C
Is that a 7? What is that?
那是 7 吗 那是个什么
I'll tell you what it is.
我跟你看看那是什么
I told you she shouldn't have made that phone call!
我跟你说了 她不该那么打电话
We lost visual on target.
视野内目标消失
All right. Shake the tree.
好吧 毁掉整座房子
-You'll pay for the breakage? -Yeah, Roger that.
-你赔钱吗 -收到 别废话
That's right, old man!
你猜对了 老东西
-Old man? -No respect.
-老东西 -真不尊重人
Can I kill her now?
现在我可以干掉她了吧
She called me an old man.
她骂我老东西
Pig! Open the pig!
猪猪 你的猪猪
Grenade!
手榴弹
Damn satellites!
去你的卫星
You just stay right there.
你就待那儿别动
This is gonna be good.
这样就很好
You okay?
你没事吧
What are you doing?
你要干什么
Old man, my ass.
骂我老 吃屎吧
God damn it!
该死的
-Smoke and thermals. Obstructed view. -Signal's fading.
-烟雾高温 视野受阻 -信号衰落
Nice shot.
枪神在世啊
-Thanks. -We should get out of here.
-谢谢 -我们得离开这里
You really know how to show a girl a good time, Frank.
真有你的 知道在女人面前秀一把的时机 弗兰克
I will kill you, Marvin.
闭上嘴 马文
Take it easy, man. She likes you.
放松伙计 她喜欢你
How can you tell?
你怎么知道
Notice how she sticks around?
没看到她老跟着你吗
'Cause if women don't like you, they don't stick around.
如果女人不喜欢你 她们不会跟着你
She doesn't have much of a choice. Does she?
她别无选择 不是吗
Sure she does.
当然可以
Really?
真的吗
You think so?
你这么觉得
You know, if it is the CIA,
你明白的 如果真是中情局
then there's only one place that we can go
那么就只有一个地方
to find out why they're coming after us.
能查清他们为什么追杀我们
We're gonna get killed there, for sure.
去那儿也等于自杀 当然了
In or out?
干不干
No. Of course I'm in. I'm just saying.
当然干了 我只是唠叨 两句
We're gonna need some serious help.
我们需要一些靠谱的支援
This is not the kind of help I meant, Frank.
这不是我说的那种支援 弗兰克
You're not actually gonna go in there, are you?
你不是真要进去吧
I don't think I can go, Frank.
我不敢进去 弗兰克
The last time they put some electrical wires in some not very nice places.
上回 他们把电线 缠在匪夷所思的地方
Listen, hang onto that for me.
听着 帮我拿着这个
I'll be right back.
我很快就回来
Be careful.
小心
Tell Ivan Simanov that Frank Moses is...
通知伊万·西曼诺夫 弗兰克·摩西
Frank Moses is here to see him.
弗兰克·摩西来了
I have to say
不得不说
this is the last thing I expected …… when I got up this morning.
这是今早醒来以后 …我最没预料到的事
I have many times dreamed of killing you.
多少次 我做梦都想杀了你
But now …you are …a pensioner.
现在呢…你…都领养老金了
Couple of years now.
都两年了
Time passes. As we get older, things seem less important.
时过境迁 当我们老去 很多事看上去都不那么重要了
Still …I owe you …for killing Igor.
但…我欠你…你除掉了伊戈尔
-Igor the Butcher. -He was a great asset.
-屠夫伊戈尔 -他是笔巨大的财富
-He was a pig. -He was my cousin.
-他就是头猪 -他是我表弟
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
To Igor. The Butcher.
敬伊戈尔 屠夫
He's not dead. I flipped him.
他没死 我掉包了
No.
不会吧
He owns a string of 7-Elevens in Orange County.
他现在香桔市 开 7-11 连锁店
He weighs 500 pounds.
他500磅重
Drink.
干杯
Who are we drinking to now?
这杯敬谁
Veronique.
维罗妮卡
She was mine.
她是我的
-Impossible. -Yes!
-不可思议 -是啊
Whatever she got, it was worth it.
不管她去哪儿了 这都值了
I miss the old days.
真怀念老时候啊
I haven't killed anyone in years.
我都好几年没杀人了
That's sad.
好可怜
But …I think you are not here for the vodka.
不过 我觉得你不是来喝伏特加的吧
I'm going to break into the CIA.
我要闯进中情局
I need your complete security layout of Langley.
我需要你提供 兰利完整的安全布局
Cracks. Codes. ID swipes.
漏洞 密码 身份识别卡
All of it.
所有东西
Amusing as this would be,
虽然这很有趣
it is beyond my reach.
不过超出我能力范围了
A favor from Frank Moses?
弗兰克·摩西求我了 哇
I can't believe you're actually letting me come along.
真不敢相信 你竟然让我过来了
The badges Ivan gave us are for a General Harlow
伊万给的徽章 是哈罗将军
and a female nuclear physicist from Los Alamos.
和阿拉莫斯实验室的女核物理学家的
You're adopted.
接受
This is so cool.
好酷啊
What?
怎么了
I dropped it.
掉地上了
Freeze!
不许动
The General has dropped his contact lens.
将军的隐形眼镜掉了
Perhaps you'd like to help us?
能帮我们找找吗
Sorry.
对不起
Found it! I found it!
找到了 我找到了
I found it.
我找到了
Have a good day, sir.
工作愉快 长官
Gentlemen.
先生们
My God!
天哪
What do you suppose the punishment is for what we're doing here?
你有没有想过 如果失败了会被怎样
Death.
死刑
Maybe life in prison.
或终身监禁
Awesome.
棒极了
Why are you holding that button?
为什么按那个按钮
The Russians give you the code?
俄罗斯人给你密码了
No.
没有
Changes every six hours.
密码每六小时会换
Will you hold that for me for a second?
能帮我拿一下吗
It's unbreakable.
这是坚不可摧的
Come on.
来吧
Mr. Moses!
摩西先生
Been a long time.
好久不见了
I'm gonna need to see that Guatemala file.
我来查看一下 危地马拉的档案
Guatemala?
危地马拉
I think I can help you.
我想我能帮上忙
Great.
太好了
It's been a whole new world around here since you left.
你离开后 这里都改天换地了
Guatemala.
危地马拉
You know, you're gonna catch hell for this.
你要知道 你可能因此下地狱的
After what I've seen?
我看过之后吗
Oh, I should tell you,
对了 有点事你得知道
there's a new guy came down here yesterday looking for your file.
昨天一个新家伙过来看你的资料
Name of William Cooper?
叫什么 威廉·库珀
6'1"? Cute hair?
高六尺一 可爱的头发
Hair was cute.
头发的确挺逗的
But I thought he looked a little tough, though.
尽管如此 我看他也算个难缠货呢
You take good care of yourself, Henry.
自己多保重 亨利
You, too, Mr. Moses.
你也是 摩西先生
Change of plan.
计划有变
Bad move, Grandpa.
来错了 老爷爷
Kordesky trained you?
柯德斯基 训练你的吗
I trained Kordesky.
我训练的柯德斯基
Son of a bitch!
狗娘养的
Seal the building. Bald, white male, 50s,
封锁大楼 光头 白种男性 五十来岁
wearing white shirt, blue pants, shot in the shoulder.
白衬衣 蓝裤子 肩部中枪
We should go.
我们得走了
We should go now.
现在就得走
I've got checkpoints at every exit. What about the fire?
每个出口都有检查点 火灾怎么办
Shut off the alarm. I told you, there is no fire!
关掉警报 我告诉你了 根本没火灾
-We need to evacuate. -No, this is just a diversion.
-我们得紧急疏散 -不 这是调虎离山
You make sure everyone gets checked.
确保每个人都接受检查
Help, help! Please come!
救命 救命 快到这边
I can't stop the bleeding.
他不停的流血
You okay, sir?
你没事吧 先生
Make a hole!
让一下
Hold it. Let me see him.
等一下 让我看一下
It's not him.
不是他
Fellas, help me out, here.
伙计们 搭把手
Marvin?
马文
There's still something wrong with this guy's head, Frank.
这家伙脑袋还是不大清醒 弗兰克
You're really something, Joe.
真有你的 乔
Marvin, you okay?
马文 你没事吧
I don't want to talk about it.
我不想说这事儿
Joe? Joe who was dead Joe?
乔 死了的那个乔
She with us?
她是一块儿的吗
Not dead.
没死
Just retired.
只是退休了
I guess calling wasn't an option?
你不能先打个电话吗
Can we go?
可以走了吗
You let yourself get shot?
你怎么挨枪子儿了
God damn it.
该死的
Out.
出去
-You okay? -Thanks, Doc.
-没事吧 -谢谢医生
What did he get?
他偷走了什么
I have no idea.
我不知道
You just had your ass handed to you by a goddamn retiree.
你刚刚 被一个该死的退休人员 揍了一顿
What did he do?
他究竟是谁
What did Moses do to earn a lethal finding?
摩西究竟做了什么 招来这杀身之祸
I have not been read into it.
我没研究过
I like you, Cooper. You're ambitious and you get results,
我很欣赏你 库珀 你雄心勃勃干到现在
but someone just kicked in the front door of our house,
但现在 有人已经踢爆咱们家前大门了
so you better get your shit straight.
你最好振作起来 做好自己的事
Nothing in your mission is changed.
你的任务 没有任何改变
You're still bleeding.
你还在流血
Must have nicked something in there.
一定是皮下有伤口了
This is so bad.
这太糟糕了
It's not that bad. People get shot all the time.
不算太糟 人们随时都会中枪的
No, they don't, they get paper cuts.
胡说 常人只是被纸割伤手指
I mostly get shot.
我就经常中弹
We're gonna have to find somebody to plug this leak.
我们得找个人缝补伤口
Could go to Eagle's Nest.
那就去鹰巢吧
Then we all get shot.
那我们就都要挨枪子儿了
I'll just go in by myself.
我自己进去吧
Want a vest?
要穿件马甲吗
Wouldn't do any good.
那只会坏事
Frank Moses.
弗兰克·摩西
Hi, Victoria.
你好 维多利亚
Are you here to kill me?
你来杀我吗
No.
不是
You've been shot.
你中枪了
Tell Marvin to stand down before he gets hurt.
让马文老实呆着 别伤着自己
Who's the girl?
这女孩儿是谁
She's with me.
跟我一起的
-Vicky. -Joe!
-维琪 -乔
Oh, Vicky. Sexy as ever.
维琪 还是性感依旧啊
You old snake charmer.
你个英俊的老滑头
Sarah, this is Victoria. Best wet work asset in the business.
莎拉 这是维多利亚 业界最佳能手
And a true artist with an RPN.
堪称 严谨操作 的艺术家
What's that?
什么意思
I kill people, dear.
意味我杀人 亲爱的
You were lucky.
你走运了
How'd you do it?
你怎么做到的
-What? -How'd you make the transition?
什么 你怎么过渡过来的
Here you seem so calm. At ease.
你看起来是如此平静 平静如水
I love it.
我爱这生活
I love it here. I love the baking. I love the flower arranging.
我爱这里 我爱甜饼 我爱周围的花朵
I like the routine.
我喜欢有条不紊
I do get a bit restless sometimes.
我有时候真有些坐立不安
I take the odd contract on the side.
我接另一边的活儿干
I just can't stop.
我停不下来
Yeah. Tell me about it.
跟我聊聊这个
You can't just flip a switch and become someone else.
人们不能一扭头就成为另一个人
Put some pressure on it.
好好按住这里
Tell me about your lady friend.
跟我聊聊你的女朋友
Makes me think that I could actually have a life.
她让我觉得我可以拥有生活
A real life.
真正的生活
Oh, Francis, you're such a romantic.
弗兰克 你真是浪漫
What?
什么
A romantic. It's why I've always been so fond of you.
罗曼蒂克 这也是为什么我一直挺喜欢你的
Victoria...
维多利亚
You're all hard on the outside, but you are...
你外表强悍 但你…
You are gooey on the inside.
内心里多愁善感
Gooey.
多愁善感
The entire back half of the Guatemala file has been blacked out.
危地马拉的档案 几乎全被涂黑了
But there's a list. 11 names. Plus one that's been redacted.
但这张名单 11个人 多了个档案里删减的
All dead. Except for Frank and Marvin.
他们全死了 除了弗兰克和马文
All the names on the reporter's list are in the file, too,
记者名单上的人 也都出现在档案里
but she has an additional name.
但她额外提到一个人
Alexander Dunning.
亚历山大·丹宁
Somebody's protecting him.
有人在保护他
Dunning is the CEO of Browning-Orvis.
丹宁是 布朗宁-奥维斯 的总裁
Gangsters.
黑帮
Defense contractor.
国防承包商
Very connected.
非常接近了
If the CIA is protecting him, he's under surveillance.
如果中情局在保护他 他一定被严密监视
We could go see him.
我们可以去找他
You're not going without me.
没我你哪儿也不能去
We're getting the band back together. That's nice.
我们又重新在一起了 棒极了
Yeah?
什么事
We just got a tip. RED has a new target.
我们刚收到提醒 RED有新目标了
A tip?
一个提醒
FBI's on the scene.
联邦调查局介入了
I'm on my way.
我马上到
The FBI has a lookout position on the east perimeter.
FBI 在东边布防一个监视岗
Copy that.
收到
Alexander Dunning.
亚历山大·丹宁
Pleasure to see you, Secretary Baptiste.
很高兴见到您 巴蒂斯特秘书长
The pleasure is with me.
也很高兴见到你
They're in.
他们进屋了
Frank said you wanted me with you.
弗兰克说你想让我跟着你
Yes, I thought it might be nice to have a bit of girl time together.
是啊 我想 有一小段闺蜜时光 会很美妙
Get to know each other.
相互了解对方
And I just wanted to tell you that in all the years I've known Francis,
我只是想告诉你 我认识弗兰克这么多年了
I've never seen him like this.
从没见过他像现在这样
So if you break his heart, I will kill you.
所以 如果你伤了他的心 我就杀了你
And bury your body in the woods.
把你的尸体扔在烂树丛里
Oh, this is gonna be fun.
哦 这会很好玩的
Here at Browning-Orvis,
在布朗宁-奥维斯
we have a longstanding commitment to humanitarian causes
我们长期致力于人道主义
because exemplary corporate citizenship is our highest calling.
因为 成为企业公民 是我们的最高使命
As a company with global reach and global interests,
作为 具有全球影响力 和全球利益的大公司
we have global responsibilities.
我们也有全球的责任
Now sometimes I'm asked,
现在如果有人问我
if this commitment to ethical behavior affects the bottom line.
如果人道主义的承诺 影响到了底线怎么办
And my answer is always the same.
我的回答依然不变
Yes.
是的
It makes it stronger.
使命使公司强大
This is my safe room. Sound-proofed. Reinforced.
这是我的安全屋 完美隔音 钢混建造
Swept for bugs daily.
每天清清蟑螂
You could fire a gun in here. No one would ever know.
在这儿放一枪 没人听得到
Mr. Dunning.
丹宁先生
I cannot imagine a more perfect place to conduct our business.
这实在是我们谈生意的最好地方了
You do know that there's
你应该很清楚
a surcharge for any arms deliveries
向联合国武器禁运国输送武器
to countries that are embargoed by the United Nations.
是要另收附加费的
For every problem, monsieur, there is a solution.
任何问题 我的先生 都会有答案的
Excuse me.
抱歉 稍等
So how did you guys meet?
你们俩怎么认识的
We started talking on the phone.
刚开始我们通电话
I guess I liked that it wasn't real.
我大概 太喜欢虚幻了
Of course now I'm a fugitive,
当然我现在在逃亡
the CIA wants to kill me and I'm hiding in a hole.
中情局要我的命 我东藏西躲的
I was in love with an agent once.
从前我和一名特工相爱
What happened?
然后呢
Well, I was with MI6.
当时我是军情六处的
And the relationship wasn't sanctioned.
我们的关系不被认可
So when it came to light, my loyalty was questioned.
后来事情浮出水面 我的忠诚面临抉择
And I was ordered to kill him.
我受命要杀了他
It was a test.
这是个考验
What did you do?
你怎么做了
I put three bullets in his chest.
我在他肩膀上打了三颗子弹
Who the hell are you guys?
你们他妈的是谁
You don't remember us?
不记得我们了
We remember you.
我们可记得你
You're the guy whose shit we cleaned up down in Guatemala in 1981.
1981年 我们在危地马拉 给你擦屁股
And the question is, who did you fly out of there?
问题是 你从那里弄出来的是谁
You don't have any idea what you're getting into.
你们 根本不懂 自己卷入的什么
First of all, you can't touch me.
首先 你动不了我
Sure, we can.
当然能了
Where'd you get this?
这个从哪儿弄得
Home Depot.
家得宝
-How much? -Ten bucks.
-多少钱 -十块
You want nuts?  Nipples? Potty trainer?
你要坚果夹 钳子 还是通便器
All right, stop it.
好啦 快住手
Nuts.
坚果夹
Stop it. For the love of Christ, stop it!
住手 看在上帝份上 住手
Now you got something to say?
你现在有话要说吗
We extracted a young lieutenant
我们救出了一名年轻上尉
who is the son of the late Senator, James Stanton.
已故参议员 詹姆斯·斯坦顿的儿子
Robert Stanton?
罗伯特·斯坦顿
Vice President of the United States.
美国副总统
You're saying the Vice President killed all the people in that village?
你的意思 是副总统 杀了全村百姓
Went completely off the reservation.
事先完全没有通知
And that New York Times reporter?
纽约时报那个记者
Did she pressure you?
她给你施压了
Yeah. She called me. Twice.
是 她打电话给我 两次
So I called the V.P.
所以我通知了副总统
And what did you think would happen then?
那你觉得 副总统会怎么做
Oh, whatever.
管他呢
I made him Vice President.
我让他当的副总统
You kept your mouth shut and the Stantons made you rich.
你闭口不谈 斯坦顿让你发财
I will pay whatever it costs
随便开个价
to get rid of this thing.
我们了结了这事
We're not here for your money, home.
我们来这里不是为了你的臭钱和房子
We're here because that New York Times reporter had the list of names
我们来这里是因为 纽约时报的记者有张名单
of everybody who was in Guatemala.
参加危地马拉任务的人都榜上有名
And everybody on that list has been ordered killed.
而名单上的所有人 都被人安排杀害了
Except you.
除了你
I had nothing to do with that.
我与此毫无关系
Don't you see?
还不明白吗
He's trying to clean up his past and get rid of me in one shot.
他在尽力洗清他的过去 并一脚把我踢开
He's trying to cut me loose before he runs for President.
试图在竞选总统之前 切断与我的所有关系
We have some major activity out here.
外边有大批警力活动
Looks like we're blown.
貌似我们要恶战了
We're in position. Perimeter's set. No one's getting out.
全体就位 方圆内 任何人都出不来
They're moving a team up the east side.
他们派一小队到东边驻守
Are you gonna let me talk to them?
你们打算让我跟他们谈谈吗
I can negotiate something.
我有资本跟他们谈判
Thanks, when we want your help, we'll get out the drain cleaner.
谢谢 如果有必要 我会拿出通便器的
Listen, Plastic Man,
听着 塑料人
those bastards out there probably have orders to kill me, too.
外边那全混蛋 很有可能也要杀了我
I hope so.
正合我意
Why? 'Cause I'm a bad guy?
为什么 因为我是坏蛋
I'm scum?
我是人渣
Can I just shoot him now?
我能现在就崩了他吗
No.
不行
You don't have people killed.
你没必要杀人
I have people killed, I'm the bad guy. Remember?
要杀人的是我 我演坏人 记得吗
Not worth a bullet.
根本不值一颗子弹
How's retirement, Frank?
退休生活怎么样 弗兰克
It's been a real blast.
惊爆透了
If we have to come in there and get you, it's gonna be messy.
如果我们强攻抓你 会一团糟的
You bet. Real messy.
你说对了 糟透了
I've got my orders, Frank.
我已经接到命令了 弗兰克
They come from the Vice President.
命令是副总统下的
He's ordered these hits to cover up the war crimes he committed in Guatemala.
他安排这一切 掩盖曾经在危地马拉犯下的战罪
I find that hard to believe.
这很难让我信服
How did you know you'd find me here?
那你是怎么找到我的呢
Some anonymous untraceable tip?
一些匿名的 不可查的 提醒吗
Here's the deal, Frank.
这是我的条件 弗兰克
You're gonna walk out that front door and give yourself up.
你从前门出来 束手就擒
You have my word no one will shoot you.
我保证没人向你们开枪
I'll personally take you in and you will get to tell your side of the story.
我亲自带你回局里 你跟他们解释你的故事
You got 60 seconds to decide.
你有 60 秒钟考虑
What's it look like?
外边情况如何
There's no clean exit.
没有好突破口
They seem to be coming from everywhere.
他们把这里包围了
If we had a distraction, I could cover you to the woods.
如果情况突变 我会掩护你进树林
Looks like there's not a lot of options, kid.
好像没有更多办法了 孩子
I mean somebody's gonna have to make the hard choice
我的意思是 必须有人做出艰难的决定
if we are gonna get out of here alive.
保证我们能安全从这里撤出去
Been wild.
野性一把
Wild and crazy.
狂野不羁
But I wouldn't want it any other way.
但我也不想以其他方式结束
An honor.
为了荣誉
Good luck.
祝你好运
Tell your men to hold their fire.
告诉你的人停火
I'm coming out.
我这就出去
He's coming out. All units, hold fire.
他要出来了 所有单位注意 停止射击
Repeat, all units, hold fire.
重复 所有单位 停止射击
Roger that.
遵命
Get behind.
躲我后边
Come out now. I've got you covered.
出来吧 我掩护你
Who fired the shot?
谁开的冷枪
Tell me when the boys make cover, we'll move.
看看大家撤出来后 告诉我一声 我们也撤
Now.
现在
They've got Sarah.
他们抓住莎拉了
Frank, you're no good to her dead.
弗兰克 她的死与你无关
We gotta move.
我们必须撤了
Now is not time to waste.
没时间浪费了
Ivan?
伊万
It's nice to see you again, Ivan.
见到你真高兴 伊万
Did he just call you "bunny"?
他刚才叫你 小兔兔
Life sometimes is complicated.
生活总是纷繁复杂的
To Joe.
敬乔
Joe.
Not to push the bounds of propriety,
别怪我说话没分寸
but don't you think we ought to discuss the fact that
但大家不该讨论一下这个事实吗
the CIA's being used by the Vice President as his personal hit squad
中情局现在已经是副总统的私人打手
and that they'll do whatever they can to find us and kill us?
他们会竭尽所能找到我们并除掉
Options?
方案吗
We could go public.
我们可以公之与众
Yeah, right. That didn't work very well for the reporter.
说的轻巧 那个记者就是这么死的
And what about Frank's girlfriend?
弗兰克女朋友怎么办
They'll kill her so fast.
他们会马上杀了她
First they'll interrogate her. They probably already got the wires.
他们会先审问她 很可能现在就已经拿着钢丝绳
Then give her a little snorkel. Give her a jump.
给她个小面罩 逼她跳河
Bring in the dent.
满身伤痕
God! You are such an idiot.
天 你真是个蠢货
I want to show you something.
我给你看样东西
This was done to me by the love of my life.
这是我生命中的至爱 留给我的
It seems that what we had was not meant to be.
也许我们所经历的 没有任何意义
But now she sits
但现在 她
outside my house
坐在我屋外
drinking vodka.
喝着伏特加
Three bullets in the chest.
肩膀上 三颗子弹
When I woke alive,
当我醒来的时候
I knew she still loved me.
我懂 她一直爱着我
Or else it would have been the head.
负责的话 早打在脑袋上了
It was big risk for her, of course,
当然 对她而言这很冒险
but one does crazy things for love.
但对爱而言 这很疯狂
Do not fear for your love, my friend.
不要恐惧你内心的爱 我的朋友
With a small dedicated group,
咱们这些个人聚在一起
there is nothing that cannot be accomplished.
没有什么不可能
Let me be blunt.
我把话挑明了吧
Nobody knows you're here. You don't exist.
没人知道你在这里 你根本不存在
And unless you cooperate fully,
除非你完全合作
there's nothing I can't do to you.
否则我们什么都干的出来
-Sir. -Not now.
-长官 -现在没空
Moses is on the phone.
摩西打电话过来
Okay. Trace is running.
好了 开始追踪
Moses.
摩西
Here's the thing, Cooper.
说心里话 库珀
With age comes a certain perspective.
人们慢慢长大有了自己的看法
I'd be a liar if I said there wasn't a time when I was exactly like you.
若说一点都不欣赏你 那是谎话
Blind ambition.
盲目的志向
Misplaced trust.
错误的信任
Why are you telling me this?
你怎么跟我扯这些
It might help me to decide what to do next.
我在决定接下来怎么行动
Just keep it going.
就这样跟他一直聊
Why? What are you thinking about?
为什么 你在考虑什么
Our business is a very hard one.
我们从事的行业很艰辛
But it was never
但一直以来
the killing or the stress,
血腥杀人 随时备战
or the bad pay that bothered me.
糟糕薪水 都从没困扰我
What was it, Frank?
那是什么 弗兰克
It's how anything that you love can be taken away from you.
困扰我的是 我该如何承受 失去我所爱
It taught me never to care.
职业让我 从不在乎什么
Never to invest.
从不专情与谁
Then I met this woman.
后来我遇上这个女人
Sarah.
莎拉
And now you have her.
而你抓了她
Now I can't think of anything more horrible
我实在想不到 能有什么事情让你害怕
than to know that your enemies can hurt someone that you love.
除了告诫你 你的敌人也能伤害你爱的人
The feeling is almost indescribable.
这种感觉无法形容
You still there, Cooper?
还在听吗 库珀
You're at my house.
你在我家
Almost indescribable, isn't it?
无法形容 不是吗
Please.
求你了
Please don't hurt my family.
求你别伤害我家人
If anything happens to Sarah,
如果莎拉少了一根头发
I will rip everything you love out of your life.
我会把你爱的人一个一个干掉
And then I'll kill you.
最后杀了你
I swear to you, I will keep Sarah safe.
我向你发誓 我确保莎拉安全
We don't have much time.
我们没多少时间
Do you understand that?
你明白吗
What are you gonna do, Frank?
你打算干什么 弗兰克
I'm gonna kill the Vice President.
我要去刺杀副总统
What are you gonna do?
你能怎么办
Frank left this for me.
弗兰克给了我这个
Where did he get it from?
他从哪里弄来的
The secure records depository of the CIA.
中情局安全档案管理库
Look, Sarah.
听着 莎拉
I know Frank's been right about a few things.
我知道 有些事情 弗兰克是对的
But he's about to cross a line from which there's no turning back.
但他正在跨过底线 走上一条不归路
Right now, you have an opportunity to help him.
现在 你有机会去救他
You need to tell me everything you know.
你必须告诉我你知道的一切
Because if I can't stop him,
因为 如果我不能阻止他
I'm gonna have to kill him.
就必须杀了他
Do you know who Frank Moses is? I mean, really is?
你知道弗兰克·摩西是谁吗 我是指 真实身份
Do you know what he's done?
你知道他干什么活的吗
You're asking me for help? That is so lame.
你是在求我帮忙 束手无策了啊
He's gonna eat you for lunch.
他会拿你做午餐
She's never gonna trust us.
她不会信任我们的
I can't blame her. The tip off was a trap.
不能怪她 之前的提醒是个圈套
Someone's got us dancing like marionettes.
我们像木偶被人玩的团团转
Just like Moses called it.
就像摩西说的那样
He will take a shot at the V.P.
他要去刺杀副总统
That's a problem for the Secret Service.
那是特勤局的问题
Moses'll take them apart.
摩西会把他们引开的
Plug me into their detail.
把我加进特勤名单
You got it.
好的
What about her?
她怎么办
I'll keep her close. Protected. Off the grid.
我会看好她 保护她 没有问题
I put a few things away.Just in case.
我私藏了一些货  以防万一
Frank.
弗兰克
Swedish K.
瑞典 K
Now that is exciting.
激动人心哪
Explosives?
有炸弹吗
Just past the RPGs.
枪榴弹那边
I love you, man.
爱死你了
-Make yourself at home. -The Vice President's gonna love this.
-随便拿 -副总统要好受一番啦
Thank you.
谢谢你
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Thank you, ma'am.
谢谢合作 夫人
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
Welcome, Ms. Brown.
热烈欢迎 布朗夫人
It's a pleasure to have you at our Victory Fund Gala.
非常感谢您能参加 胜选基金晚宴
Oh, I'm so looking forward to it.
我也迫不及待啊
Raptor is cleared for entry.
猛禽报告入口安全
After you, Mr. Vice President.
你先请 副总统先生
A true war hero, a fabulous friend and a wonderful leader.
一位真正的战争英雄 优秀的朋友 卓绝的领袖
And so it's with great pleasure I introduce to you,
非常荣幸 由我向大家介绍
vice President Robert Stanton.
副总统先生 罗伯特·斯坦顿
Thank you, everybody. Thank you so much for being here.
谢谢 谢谢大家 非常感谢大家能赏光莅临
I'm gonna keep this short and sweet
我会尽量 说的少 说的好
so you'll actually write those checks you've been promising.
这样大家才不会 给我写空头支票
Seriously, though, great to see you all.
说真的 很高兴见到大家
It's the wonderful people here tonight
正是今晚在座的各位伟大的伙伴
that got us into the White House in the first place.
让我们站在白宫的最前端
And I believe it's this wonderful group of people
而我相信 在座伟大的伙伴们
who will keep us there for a long, long time!
会支持我们在那里 很长很长时间
My good friends,
我亲爱的朋友们
I am proud to announce that I will be forming an exploratory committee
我正式宣布 组建一个竞选委员会
with the primary goal of seeking a nomination for the Presidency.
以达成伟大的目标 成功竞选总统
We've had a great journey together.
我们曾携手走过一段伟大的旅程
But I firmly believe that the best is still to come.
我也坚定的相信 最好的即将到来
God bless you all.
上帝保佑你们
God bless America!
上帝保佑美利坚
Hello, bunny.
你好 小兔兔
Moves like that could get you killed.
这样胡闹会让我杀了你
Your radiance tonight renders me almost speechless.
今晚你光彩照人 我几乎说不出话来
Almost.
差点
What are you grinning at?
你笑嘻嘻干啥呢
I've always dreamed of killing an American President.
我一直梦想 能够杀个美国总统玩玩
Vice President.
这是副总统
Whatever.
差不多啦
Having you in my arms once again, I get carried away.
再次把你拥在怀中 我得意忘形啊
Really?
真的吗
Tell me you love me.
告诉我你爱我
It's been a long time, Ivan.
已经很久了 伊万
Blink of an eye.
就一句嘛
Ivan.
伊万
The music has stopped.
音乐已经停了
Is it?
是吗
To work then.
该行动了
Ivan!
伊万
Do you smell that?
你闻到了吗
-This area is off limits. -No, it's fine. It's fine.
-本区域禁行  -没关系 没关系
You'll have to turn around.
请您回去
No, it's fine.
哦 没关系
It's all right. I'm sure I'm allowed.
没关系 我确信我有权过来
You'll have to go back up, ma'am, or I'll have to treat you as a threat.
您必须立刻回去 夫人 否则我们会视同威胁
Where exactly is the threat?
威胁究竟在哪儿
Gas! I smell gas!
煤气 有煤气
Gas! Gas!
煤气 煤气
Gas!
煤气
Stand aside.
靠边站
Primary exit blocked. Secondary, move.
常规出口封闭 备用通道 快
Move! Move! Move!
快 快 快
What the hell are they using?
他们用的什么鬼东西
Get back up in here to the north stairwell, now!
步行梯北 需要支援 快
Move to the other limo. I'll cover you.
快换另一辆车 我掩护你
We have to go. Now! Now!
我们必须撤退啦 快 快
Approaching target from the rear.
从后面接近目标
Outside!
外边
Secret Service, everybody down!
特勤局 大家都趴下
Cover us! We're moving now!
掩护我们 现在就行动
Come on! Move!
加把劲 快
I remember the Secret Service being tougher.
我记得特勤局通常很牛逼的
Me, too.
我更牛
Marvin.
马文
Bugger!
妈的
-Almost there. -Marvin.
-快到了 -马文
We gotta move.
我们得离开了
You're on your own. I'm no use anymore.
你自己走 我不能拖你后腿
Good luck. Go on.
保重 走吧
Let's move!
我们走
Are you hit, sir?
你受伤了吗 长官
-Are you hit? -I'm fine! Just get me the hell out of here.
-你受伤吗 -我很好 快点我把弄出这鬼地方
Perhaps I could be of assistance?
也许 我能帮上忙
I love you.
我爱你
I know.
我知道
Freeze!
站住
Go. Go!
快跑
Go!
快
Get in! Get in!
进去 进去
Go, go, go!
快开 快
Stop the car! Stop...
停车 停车
Don't you dare stop! You keep going!
不准停 快开车
Stop the car! Pull over!
停车 靠边停车
I wanna know what the hell that was all about!
我要查清 这一切究竟是他妈怎么回事
Get him off!
把他摔下去
Pull over!
靠边停车
Raptor is secure.
猛禽安全
Who are you?
你是谁
One of the men you ordered killed.
一个你准备除掉的人
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不知道你在说些什么
Guatemala.
危地马拉
I was there.
我参与了
I'm sure we can negotiate something.
我觉得 我们应该谈谈
Starting to come back to you now, is it?
开始露出本身熊样了 啊
If you're looking for revenge...
如果你要复仇
This is not about revenge.
这与复仇无关
Are you gonna kill me?
你会杀了我吗
Not just you.
不止你
I'm at the Evanston power plant.
我在埃文斯顿 发电厂
You have 15 minutes to bring me Sarah.
你有 15 分钟把莎拉带过来
Or I kill the vice President.
不然我就杀了副总统
He just made contact. He wants the girl.
摩西带电话来了 他要那姑娘
Evanston Power Station. 15 minutes.
埃文斯顿 发电厂 15 分钟
You better alert Secret Service.
你最好通知特勤局
Copy that.
收到
Secret Service is en route.
特勤局 已上路
Where's Sarah?
莎拉呢
She's on her way.
路上呢
It's over, Frank.
结束了 弗兰克
Any minute the whole world is gonna drop on you.
每一分钟 这个世界都在抛弃你
We'll see.
走着瞧
Hey, tough guy.
嘿 壮汉
Surprised to see me?
见到我很惊讶吧
What the hell's this?
这究竟怎么回事
Alex...
艾利克斯
Just give him what he wants. I can't do this anymore.
他要什么都给他 我再也不干了
You ordered these killings, not me.
你下的追杀令 不是我
I don't want to have anything to do with this anymore.
我再也 不想跟这破事 有任何干系啦
You shot me.
你打我
Shut up.
闭嘴
I loved watching you being a good guy.
我喜欢看你演好人
Kicking ass for your country.
为你的国家 奔走效命
It showed a spectacular lack of vision.
你真是缺乏远见 蠢到家了
The girl goes free.
把女孩儿放了
That'll cost you a gun.
那你得挨一枪
A life for a life.
一命换一命
I tore up all those checks.
我把养老支票都撕了
I know.
我知道
I just wanted to talk to you.
我只想过跟你说会儿话
Cooper
库珀
cuff him.
把他铐上
Wilkes told me you had promise.
威尔克斯 说你发过誓
Okay, here's how it goes.
好吧 事情这么办
Moses just shot the V.P.
摩西要枪杀副总统
You kill him and the girl,
你击毙了摩西和女孩儿
and you're head of the CIA.
然后你做中情局的头儿
Cooper.
库珀
This is gonna happen either way.
不管怎样都会这样的
Fuck you, Cynthia.
去死吧 辛迪娅
Thanks.
谢谢你
This gonna be a problem?
他会出什么差错吗
No.
不会
I got it...
我能搞定
Grandpa.
老头子
Feel better now?
爽了吗
Yeah.
爽死了
Wanna get pancakes?
想吃甜饼吗
Can you believe it? It all worked out.
你相信吗 梦想成真啦
Something bad is gonna happen very soon.
坏事情马上会发生
Maybe not. Wait a second.
也许不会 等一下
Nobody's chasing us.
没人追我们了
No one's trying to kill us.
没人要杀我们
I think we just got our lives back.
我想我们又恢复常态了
Almost.
差点
You still owe me a small favor.
你还得替我干一件小事
His timing is terrible.
真不会挑时候
You gave a favor to him?
他给你一件任务
Just a tiny little nuclear problem in Moldova.
就一件 小小的 摩尔多瓦的 核问题
Can we go?
我能去吗
Yes. We can go.
当然 我们都去
I told you something bad was gonna happen.
早跟你说了 坏事情要发生
Keep your dress on.
穿上你的裙子
Moldova sucks.
摩尔多瓦糟透了
Moldova sucks!
Next time, your girlfriend can wear the dress.
下次 让你女朋友穿这裙子